<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Christodoulos Fragkoudakis</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Christodoulos Fragkoudakis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NTUA Digital Twin using FIWARE tools</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/ntuadt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/ntuadt/</guid><description>I document how I utilized the FIWARE ecosystem to develop a Digital Twin for the NTUA Campus. I provide my work for disseminating knowledge about FIWARE under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
Introduction # This paper documents the approach of Urban Water Management and Hydroinformatcs Group in NTUA to create a Digital Twin for the NTUA campus. We chose to employ the FIWARE tools ecosystem and apply the necessary technical glue for the assembly of a Digital Twin data representation of NTUA&amp;rsquo;s campus environment.</description></item><item><title>Random Angular Tips</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/angular/angular-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/angular/angular-tips/</guid><description>How to chain observables # If observable2 (getAuthorizedApplications) depends on a finished observable1 (getSubjectToken) you can utilize mergeMap from rxjs:
class SomeClass { ... onCredentials(credentials: Credentials) { this.auth .getSubjectToken(credentials) .pipe( map((res) =&amp;gt; res.headers.get(&amp;#39;X-Subject-Token&amp;#39;) ?? &amp;#39;&amp;#39;), tap((subjectToken) =&amp;gt; { localStorage.setItem(&amp;#39;X-Subject-Token&amp;#39;, subjectToken); }), mergeMap((subjectToken) =&amp;gt; { return this.auth.getAuthorizedApplications(subjectToken); }) ) .subscribe((res) =&amp;gt; console.log(res)); } ... }</description></item><item><title>Orion Context Broker</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/orion-context-broker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/orion-context-broker/</guid><description>The FIWARE ecosystem # There is vast chaos of available software technologies regarding possible approaches to a Digital Twin implementation. I am a complete newbie in the area, having a background in computer science and IT implementations in NTUA. It is a fortunate coincidence that I can capitalize on my experience and immediately utilize the plethora of excellent available tools and practices, most notably the FIWARE ecosystem.
The heart of any Digital Twin implementation is a system for managing context information.</description></item><item><title>DHCP reservation for a kvm virtual machine</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/virtmanager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/virtmanager/</guid><description>In case you need a DHCP reservation for a kvm virtual machine, say for the debian11 one, you should first find the machine&amp;rsquo;s mac address:
$ virsh dumpxml debian11 | grep &amp;#39;mac address&amp;#39; &amp;lt;mac address=&amp;#39;52:54:00:6a:c0:15&amp;#39;/&amp;gt; Then find the network name:
virsh net-list Name State Autostart Persistent -------------------------------------------- default active yes yes and edit the XML configuration:
$ virsh net-edit default &amp;lt;network&amp;gt; &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;default&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt; &amp;lt;uuid&amp;gt;f2e7f420-1cf3-4535-8469-d3dfdaaf9ffc&amp;lt;/uuid&amp;gt; &amp;lt;forward mode=&amp;#39;nat&amp;#39;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;bridge name=&amp;#39;virbr0&amp;#39; stp=&amp;#39;on&amp;#39; delay=&amp;#39;0&amp;#39;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;mac address=&amp;#39;52:54:00:a9:7e:b5&amp;#39;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ip address=&amp;#39;192.</description></item><item><title>On Storing Data Models</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/storing-data-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/storing-data-models/</guid><description>Without a Realtime Database # Most Digital Twin projects require communication between several endpoints. These endpoints can be anything from devices and services to applications, and eventually, data needs to be stored somewhere for further processing and analysis.
So let’s say you want to build a Digital Twin where a device will measure temperature and humidity values from sensors and send them to a database service to store them. Then you want to have a web application that will fetch these values and display them in a dashboard.</description></item><item><title>The big picture</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/the-big-picture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/the-big-picture/</guid><description>A bird’s eye view of a Digital Twin implementation that incorporates modern technological advancements could be depicted in the following figure. Clients are running the Digital Twin’s frontend that displays objects bound to backend entities. The front-end implementation uses “observable” constructs, adjusting displayed objects to “live” back-end queries. The backend implementation involves a sensor cloud that constantly updates a real-time database. The real-time database automatically pushes updates to every connected client.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to mongoengine</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/python/mongoengine-primer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/python/mongoengine-primer/</guid><description>MongoEngine is an Object-Document Mapper, written in Python for working with MongoDB. To install it, simply run
python -m pip install -U mongoengine dnspython Lets connect to an Atlas database and save a sample User document:
from mongoengine import * connect( db=&amp;#34;myFirstDB&amp;#34;, username=&amp;#34;username&amp;#34;, password=&amp;#34;password&amp;#34;, host=&amp;#34;mongodb+srv://whatever.mongodb.net/db&amp;#34;, alias=&amp;#34;mydb&amp;#34;, ) class User(Document): username = StringField() password = StringField() meta = {&amp;#34;db_alias&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;mydb&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;collection&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;users&amp;#34;} User(username=&amp;#34;username&amp;#34;, password=&amp;#34;password&amp;#34;).save() The above code saves a new document into the user collection of the myFirstDB database:</description></item><item><title>Μαθησιακό υλικό Coding Factory 2022</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/teaching/coding-factory/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/teaching/coding-factory/</guid><description>Μαθησιακό υλικό για το πρόγραμμα Coding Factory του ΟΠΑ
MongoDB # Δημιουργία λογαριασμού στην υπηρεσία Atlas Heroku # Εγκατάσταση του Git Δημιουργία λογαριασμού στην υπηρεσία Heroku Εγκατάσταση του heroku cli Python # Εγκατάσταση Python IDE Εισαγωγή στην Python Εισαγωγή στο Web programming με Python</description></item><item><title>On determining the outer shell of a unit cube complex</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/addoptml/unit-cube-complex/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/addoptml/unit-cube-complex/</guid><description>Christodoulos Fragkoudakis and Markos Karampatsis
This report results from our research and development during our secondment in IDEA75 between 1/6/2021 and 31/11/2021. Our work program was “WP1” “Development of topology-sizing design optimization methodology incorporating nonlinear FEM analyses and machine learning” as described in Annex 1 of the Grant Agreement.
A Python class for 3D Points # We will assemble a python class that represents 3D points and supports basic operations between its instances.</description></item><item><title>Neovim setup</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/neovim-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/neovim-setup/</guid><description>Setup neovim like an IDE # The following setup runs in WSL2 (Ubuntu 20.04) in a Windows 10 machine. Start by installing neovim and creating an empty configuration file:
sudo apt install neovim mkdir .config/nvim touch .config/nvim/init.vim I proceeded with repeated &amp;ldquo;checkhealth&amp;rdquo; commands in neovim and tried to fix the errors. These were the required steps:
Python 2 installation # In Ubuntu 20.04 there is neither python2 installed nor a pip2 command available.</description></item><item><title>Basic Linux Installation</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/linux/</guid><description>Network configuration # Interface setup (static IP) # Adjust the following according to your network details:
auto ens160 iface ens160 inet static address 192.168.170.100 netmask 255.255.255.0 network 192.168.170.0 broadcast 192.168.170.255 gateway 192.168.170.200 dns-nameservers &amp;lt;ip of your domain dns&amp;gt; dns-search your.domain.com Setup an interface as a gateway # In the following setup interface eth0 is connected to the internet while eth1 is the gateway of the internal lan that forwards traffic to eth0</description></item><item><title>LTSP setup for a university classroom</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/ltsp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/ltsp/</guid><description>Warning: This is my personal notepad for such installations.
Use it at your own risk!
First steps # Start with a fresh and minimal ubuntu installation as it is depicted here. A functional (but with limited functionality) LTSP server is just a matter of the following commands:
sudo apt get update sudo apt get upgrade sudo apt install ltsp-server-standalone sudo ltsp-build-client DHCP server setup # You should configure the network interface from which the server should respond to requests:</description></item><item><title>Team Work</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/writings/team-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/writings/team-work/</guid><description>There are four people named Everybody, Somebody, Anybody and Nobody. There was an important job to be done and Everybody was asked to do it. Everybody was sure Somebody would do it, Anybody could have done it but Nobody did it.
Somebody got angry about that because it was Everybody&amp;rsquo;s job. Everybody thought Anybody could do it, but Nobody realized that Everybody wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do it. It ended up that Everybody blamed Somebody when Nobody did what Anybody could have done.</description></item><item><title>CentOS 5.x notes</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/legacy-centos-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/legacy-centos-notes/</guid><description>My personal notebook for CentOS 5.x installations.
Enable LDAP authentication # If the IP of your LDAP server is 10.10.10.10 and your base dn is ou=users,dc=yourdomain,dc=com then the following command enables LDAP authentication:
authconfig --enableldap --enableldapauth \ --ldapserver=10.10.10.10 \ --ldapbasedn=ou=users,dc=yourdomain,dc=com \ --enablecache --useshadow \ --enablelocauthorize --enablemkhomedir --update Enable network bonding # You need two network interfaces. Interface eth0 configuration recides in /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-eth0:
DEVICE=eth0 BOOTPROTO=none ONBOOT=yes MASTER=bond0 SLAVE=yes The same holds for eth1 in /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-eth1:</description></item><item><title>ImageMagick magic</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/imagemagick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/linux/imagemagick/</guid><description>ImageMagick is an excellent tool for any image manipulation you can imagine. Check out the following commands.
Add an one pixel black boder around image # convert &amp;lt;source image&amp;gt; -shave 1x1 -bordercolor black -border 1 &amp;lt;target image&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Need for speed</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/writings/need-for-speed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/writings/need-for-speed/</guid><description>(άλλες φορές αργός θάνατος)
Φάνηκε από πριν ότι θα ζούσα περιπέτεια. Ξεπρόβαλε με μεγάλη ταχύτητα από την υπόγεια διάβαση και σταμάτησε 10 μέτρα μετά τη στάση. Ξεκίνησε πριν προλάβω να πατήσω στέρεα κι έτσι προσγειώθηκα ανώμαλα στα καθίσματα ακριβώς μπροστά στα σκαλοπάτια της εισόδου. Κατά την προσφιλή τους τακτική η έκδοση των εισητηρίων άρχισε λίγο μετά την Αγία Παρασκευή και στη συνέχεια κοίταζαν με βλέμα αρπακτικού:
&amp;ldquo;Άλλος για εισητήριο! Μα τέσσερις δεν μπήκαν (μονολογεί) που είναι ο τελευταίος;&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Στέλιος</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/writings/stelios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/writings/stelios/</guid><description>Προαντιπαραπροχθές πήγαμε στο ένα πετ σοπ του Πικερμίου για να πάρουμε ένα χρυσόψαρο για το μικρό. Μετά τον εγκάρδιο χαιρετισμό του καταστηματάρχη μας σνόμπαρε τελείως όταν του είπαμε ότι θέλουμε χρυσόψαρο και γυάλα.
&amp;ldquo;Πφφφ! &amp;hellip; χρυσόψαρο! &amp;hellip; και γυάλα!!!&amp;rdquo;
είπε με τόσο έντονη αηδία που με έκανε να του χαμογελάσω συγκαταβατικά όταν κανονικά θα ήθελα να τον βρίσω και όπως πάντα αυτός το πήρε σαν πρόσκληση να συνεχίσει το μπουλούστισμα (Ναξιώτικος όρος, δεν είμαι σίγουρος για την ορθογραφία, το αναφέρω για να σωθεί η ντοπιολαλιά, σημαίνει ότι κάποιος πάει να σου πασάρει κάτι που δεν χρειάζεσαι εξυμμνώντας ταυτόχρονα την ποιότητα και την αξία του).</description></item><item><title>Μπούργος - Πορτάρα - Γρόττα</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/naxos/2006-01-01-mpourgos-portara-grotta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/naxos/2006-01-01-mpourgos-portara-grotta/</guid><description>Γραπτό του αείμνηστου πατέρα μου Γιώργου Φραγκουδάκη:
Θα προσπαθήσω να κάνω μια παρουσίαση των πιο πάνω περιοχών. Είναι σ&amp;rsquo; όλους γνωστό, ότι ένα μέρος της παλιάς Χώρας, που βρίσκεται βόρεια του ενετικού κάστρου, ονομάζεται Μπούργος (λέξη λατινική που σημαίνει οχυρωμένη πόλη) κι ακόμη βορειότερα του Μπούργου απλώνεται ο ιστορικός, μυθικός, γεμάτος φυσικές ομορφιές ορμίσκος της Γρόττας (λέξη λατινική που σημαίνει θαλασσινή σπηλιά). Αυτά που θα γράψω τα έχω ακούσει από διηγήσεις μεγαλύτερων, μου τα δίδαξαν οι δάσκαλοί μου ή τα διάβασα.</description></item><item><title>Αλυκές της Νάξου</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/naxos/alukes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/naxos/alukes/</guid><description>Διήγηση του αείμνηστου πατέρα μου Γιώργου Φραγκουδάκη:
Δίπλα στη δυτική πλευρά του σημερινού αεροδρομίου, το έδαφος ήταν αμμώδες, επίπεδο και το υψόμετρο ήταν ελάχιστο. Το έλουζε η αλμύρα της διπλανής θάλασσας και γι’ αυτό ήταν τελείως ακατάλληλο για γεωργική εκμετάλευση. Εκεί υπήρχαν όλες οι προϋποθέσεις για να δημιουργηθούν και λειτουργήσουν οι αλυκές της Νάξου.
Έμπειροι αγροτοεργάτες από το διπλανό χωριό το Αγερσανί ανοίγουν στν άμμο λεκάνες σε σχήμα ορθογώνιο, αρκετού μήκους και πλάτους, που είχαν βάθος εβδομήντα εκατοστά περίπου.</description></item><item><title>Βυρσοδεψία της Νάξου</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/naxos/vyrsodepsia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/naxos/vyrsodepsia/</guid><description>Διήγηση του αείμνηστου πατέρα μου Γιώργου Φραγκουδάκη:
Η χρησιμοποίηση δερμάτων για την κάλυψη πρωταρχικών αναγκών του ανθρώπου, οδήγησε από πολύ πρώϊμα στην αναζήτηση τρόπου κατασκευής τους. Για να γίνει η δέψη του δέρματος απαιτείται πολύ νερό και αρκετή αιολική δύναμη (δεδομένου ότι οι μηχανές ντίζελ τότε σπάνιζαν). Βέβαια απαράιτητη ήταν και η ύπαρξη ζωϊκών δερμάτων που η Νάξος διέθετε σε αφθονία.
Η περιοχή της Γρόττας της Νάξου πρόσφερε σε αφθονία νερό και μεγάλη αιολικλη δύναμη.</description></item><item><title>Σιδηρουργία της Νάξου</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/naxos/sidirourgia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/naxos/sidirourgia/</guid><description>Διήγηση του αείμνηστου πατέρα μου Γιώργου Φραγκουδάκη:
Η Νάξος με ανεπτυγμένη γεωργία είχε απόλυτη ανάγκη από σιδερένια γεωργικά εργαλεία: τσάπες, δρεπάνια, φτυάρια, κασμάδες, λοστοί και άλλα πολλά. Η κάλυψη της ανάγκης αυτής δημιούργησε τα σιδηρουργεία.
Ένα απ&amp;rsquo; αυτά, το πλέον φημισμένο στη Νάξο, ήταν του Γιάννη Σαλτερή. Στο έμπα της Χώρας, απέναντι στο γραφικό εκκλησάκι του Αγίου Μάρκου, το οποίο μέχρι και σήμερα διατηρείται όπως ήταν τη δεκαετία του 1930. Σιδηρουργείο με τα όλα του.</description></item></channel></rss>