<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>digital twins on Christodoulos Fragkoudakis</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/tags/digital-twins/</link><description>Recent content in digital twins on Christodoulos Fragkoudakis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://fragkoudakis.gr/tags/digital-twins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NTUA Digital Twin using FIWARE tools</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/ntuadt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/ntuadt/</guid><description>I document how I utilized the FIWARE ecosystem to develop a Digital Twin for the NTUA Campus. I provide my work for disseminating knowledge about FIWARE under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
Introduction # This paper documents the approach of Urban Water Management and Hydroinformatcs Group in NTUA to create a Digital Twin for the NTUA campus. We chose to employ the FIWARE tools ecosystem and apply the necessary technical glue for the assembly of a Digital Twin data representation of NTUA&amp;rsquo;s campus environment.</description></item><item><title>On Storing Data Models</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/storing-data-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/storing-data-models/</guid><description>Without a Realtime Database # Most Digital Twin projects require communication between several endpoints. These endpoints can be anything from devices and services to applications, and eventually, data needs to be stored somewhere for further processing and analysis.
So let’s say you want to build a Digital Twin where a device will measure temperature and humidity values from sensors and send them to a database service to store them. Then you want to have a web application that will fetch these values and display them in a dashboard.</description></item><item><title>The big picture</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/the-big-picture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/the-big-picture/</guid><description>A bird’s eye view of a Digital Twin implementation that incorporates modern technological advancements could be depicted in the following figure. Clients are running the Digital Twin’s frontend that displays objects bound to backend entities. The front-end implementation uses “observable” constructs, adjusting displayed objects to “live” back-end queries. The backend implementation involves a sensor cloud that constantly updates a real-time database. The real-time database automatically pushes updates to every connected client.</description></item></channel></rss>