<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>digital twins on Christodoulos Fragkoudakis</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/tags/digital-twins/</link><description>Recent content in digital twins on Christodoulos Fragkoudakis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://fragkoudakis.gr/tags/digital-twins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Orion Context Broker</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/orion-context-broker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/orion-context-broker/</guid><description>The FIWARE ecosystem # There is vast chaos of available software technologies regarding possible approaches to a Digital Twin implementation. I am a complete newbie in the area, having a background in computer science and IT implementations in NTUA. It is a fortunate coincidence that I can capitalize on my experience and immediately utilize the plethora of excellent available tools and practices, most notably the FIWARE ecosystem.
The heart of any Digital Twin implementation is a system for managing context information.</description></item><item><title>On Storing Data Models</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/storing-data-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/storing-data-models/</guid><description>Without a Realtime Database # Most Digital Twin projects require communication between several endpoints. These endpoints can be anything from devices and services to applications, and eventually, data needs to be stored somewhere for further processing and analysis.
So let’s say you want to build a Digital Twin where a device will measure temperature and humidity values from sensors and send them to a database service to store them. Then you want to have a web application that will fetch these values and display them in a dashboard.</description></item><item><title>The big picture</title><link>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/the-big-picture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fragkoudakis.gr/posts/digital-twins/the-big-picture/</guid><description>A bird’s eye view of a Digital Twin implementation that incorporates modern technological advancements could be depicted in the following figure. Clients are running the Digital Twin’s frontend that displays objects bound to backend entities. The front-end implementation uses “observable” constructs, adjusting displayed objects to “live” back-end queries. The backend implementation involves a sensor cloud that constantly updates a real-time database. The real-time database automatically pushes updates to every connected client.</description></item></channel></rss>